ANIL YUKSEL

FRONT-END WEB DEVELOPER

SUMMARY

Front-end developer with extensive background in education and a passion for user experience, interaction design, strength in creative and strategic thinking. Learning and growing as a developer are important to me and I am currently working on 3+ front-end projects for my diploma program. I have gained significant experience from my previous jobs, and I can use these experiences in my current profession. Working as a basketball referee has given me a lot of great experience, such as working as a team, good communication, thinking quickly and taking quick action. Engineering, on the other hand, helped me developing skills in problem solving. I am excellent in working in teams and enjoy collaboration with peers; Also, I believe that my passion for web development and my skills in problem-solving would make me a great asset to your team.

SKILLS

JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML, CSS, ReactJS, NodeJS, Express, React Router, Redux, Bootstrap, SASS/SCSS, Mongoose, Material UI, RestApi, MongoDB, Git, GitHub.

PROJECTS

Netflix Clone Mar. 2022

It's a full stack React project that I made a clone of Netflix. It's almost the same as Netflix. It is still developing phase.

Tech: React, Redux, TypeScript, NodeJs, Express, MongoDb, Mongoose, SASS/SCSS.

Blog-Application-MERN

Feb. 2022

Fully deployed full stack React application that allows users to register or login and all crud operations. In addition to that they can share comments to other user's entries.

Tech: React, Redux, TypeScript, NodeJs, Express, MongoDb, Mongoose, JWT, Bootstrap

Movie Application Dec. 2021

It is a Movie Listing application using self-created fake Api and users can see general information about movies and watch trailers.

Tech: React, Context Api, Bootstrap

Weather Application Oct. 2021

React project using weather Api and show the weather conditions of the user's current location.

Tech: React, RestApi

EDUCATION

Cornerstone International Community College of Canada

Diploma, Web, and Mobile App Development | May 2021 - April 2022 | Vancouver, British Columbia, Canada

Middle East Technical University

Bachelor's Degree, Geological Engineering | Oct 2015 - Feb 2021 | Ankara, Turkey

EMPLOYMENT

Intern-Geological Engineer

TPIC - Turkish Petroleum International Company Ltd. | July 2018 - Sep 2018 | Batman, Turkey

Basketball Referee

Turkish Basketball Federation | March 2015 - July 2018 | Ankara, Turkey